# Mudit Gupta

**E-mail:** es14btech11012@iith.ac.in **Phone:** +91-9705731498, +91-9782325393

#### **Education**

B.Tech. 2014 — 2018

#### **IIT Hyderabad**

Engineering Science => CGPA - 7.55, Minor in Entrepreneurship => CGPA - 9

### **Summary**

I am a passionate Developer, Techy Geek and an Explorer. Interested in Product Management. Worked on projects related to React.js, node.js, Android, GoLang, data analysis, Machine Learning etc. Also worked as Manager for Elan & Nvision IIT Hyderabad (cultural and technical fest of IIT Hyderabad) and E-Cell (Entrepreneurship Cell) IIT Hyderabad. I like to explore and try out various things and so in turn learn a lot of things.

### Work experience (Tech)

Aerospike May 2017 — June 2017

**Software Engineering Intern** (Guide - Khosrow Afroozeh, Technical Lead And Sunil Sayyaparaju, Director - Product & Technology)

- Developed AMC-Agent, a distributed monitoring service developed in **Go Language.**.
- Developed core framework to stream any data from the individual nodes to a central server based on commands.
- · Implemented commands to stream log files or extracted content based on specific filters.
- Implemented capability to query for content in a given time range across multiple split log files.

Carrot ID December 2015 — March 2016

Developer (Guide - Adi Vemuru, Founder CarrotID & The August Fest)

- Made a website with Dynamic front-end using React and Redux.
- Followed Agile Development Process

# **Projects**

- Security Access Logging (Objective To make iotivity devices more secure) Building a logging system in lotivity, rule based vulnerability analysis module and attack prevention module.
- **Veedion** Presently working on an e-learning platform for lifelong learners. Learned about Market Research, Business Plan Development, Entrepreneurship.
- **Hunger Torrent** Co-Founded Hunger torrent as food delivery service which was operational at IIT Hyderabad for 2 months. Learned about Idea validation, execution of idea and much more.
- DYDE Made front end of Android app using XML and Java in Android Studio. Used various layouts and views. Also made a static website using bootstrap.
- Meteor Starter Kit (https://github.com/mudit1403/Zen) Made a meteor react react router starter kit and for the demo of
  that starter kit I made login and registration page using that kit.
   Key Concepts Demonstrated React with Meteor, Basic routing with React Router, Routes requiring authentication, Working
  with reactive data.
- Tweet Analysis (Guide Prof. Maunendra Sankar Desarkar) Worked on a Machine Learning Classification problem to classify news channel tweets into various categories.
- Detecting Sub-Events associated with the main event (Guide Prof. Srijith pk) (https://github.com/mudit1403/Twitter-Sub-Event).

# Skills

- Languages Golang, C, C++, Python, Java, Javascript, Fortran
- WebBased Languages HTML, CSS, JS
- PostgreSQL, MongoDb
- Frameworks and Libraries React.js, Reflux, Redux, Meteor, Node.js, Express
- Android App Development XML, React Native
- · Machine Learning, Data Analysis

#### **Interests**

My interests include

- Learning new things and gaining new experiences.
- Entrepreneurship.
- · Developing new things.
- Product Management

#### **Relevant Academic Courses Done**

- Computer Networks
- Database Management Systems
- · Applied Machine Learning
- · Operating Systems
- Algorithms
- · Automata Theory and Theory of Computation
- Data Structures
- · Internet of Things

#### **Relevant Online Courses Done**

- Programming Languages Udacity
- Intro to Machine Learning, Intro to Data Analysis -Udacity
- · Android Development for Beginners, Developing Android Apps - Udacity
- · Intro to Descriptive Statistics, Intro to Inferential Statistics - Udacity
- · Machine Learning (Stanford University) Coursera
- Server-side Development with NodeJs (The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology) - Coursera
- Introduction to Software Product Management (University of Alberta) - Coursera

# Work experience (Non-Tech)

# **E-Cell IIT Hyderabad**

April 2016 — April 2017

#### Manager

- . Co-Founded and Organised Megathon which is India's largest and first ever student run Hackathon in association with E-Cell, IIIT Hyderabad with more than 500 participants.
- · Leading the startup culture at IIT Hyderabad. I conducted various events, workshops, interactive games and speaker sessions for inspiring and assisting young entrepreneurs in their journey in the world of business.

# Elan & Nvision 2017 IIT Hyderabad

April 2016 — April 2017

- Manager
  - · Conducted the best fest IIT-H has ever seen with triple the budget and famous personalities performing on stage.
  - · Leaded a team of 25 Coordinators and around 100 volunteers.
  - Took care of Sponsorship and Workshops Deals, Finances, Hospitality and Infrastructure.
  - . Took care of Fest Management and ensured smooth running of the Fest.

#### **Nvision 2016**

June 2015 — April 2016

#### **Marketing Co-ordinator**

- · Talked and convinced various companies to sponsor our fest.
- Leaded a team of 10 volunteers and trained them.
- . Took care of the requirements of our sponsors for various publicity like online publicity and ground publicity.
- · Coordinated with other coordinators and managers for managing the event according to the requirements of our sponsors.

# Volunteering

The August Fest - Worked as social media volunteer.

NSS - worked as a volunteer for teaching activities, cloth donation etc. for social cause.